I'm sure you watched one of
my videos that's why you're here and want to
understand the numerical side of the
policy. Watch out for the next video
so you can understand. How do you
enjoy the policy or the plan? Okay, let
's go back to our sample in the
first video. No, we have a male 30
years old non-smoker who took out a plan
with a face amount of 1 million.
He included a dental death benefit and a total
disability benefit. This is a 10-year
paying program. His annual premium
is
26,888 30 up to 39 because he has 10 years to pay. At
the end of the 6th year of the
policy year, he will start
receiving a guaranteed cash benefit
or what we call an endowment
benefit of 6% of the face amount. What is
the 6% face amount again? Of course, it's
php6,000
only starting at age 36 up to age 100.
A male 30 years old will receive 6%
or equivalent to php6,000 all throughout
the year while he lives. So
you may remember our centenarian bonus if
You still remember related to the
expanded centenarian Act of 2024 that
you will receive 10,000 as of the law,
10,000 at age 80, 85, 90 and 95 but because
the company wants to increase
your centenarian bonus that's why this
plan has a design
that you will receive at
age 80, 85, 90 and 95 equivalent to 25%
of the face amount
our sample illustration is a 1 million So what is
25% of the 1 million is
php50,000 even if you calculate that
before instances he can
receive the centenarian bonus age 80,
85, 90 and 95 So let's not forget
in reference to the centenarian app
the policy owner will receive 25% of
the face amount again the maturity
benefit will be given Once
the policy matures or Once the
policy owner's coverage is over meaning
he has survived age 100 if  He will be
101 and will receive the maturity
benefit which is a summation of the cash
value the dividends the centenarian
bonus if there is any left if there is any that
has not been received and the Dividend so
again I'm just showing you again
what is included in the maturity
benefit which is included in
our computation let's look at
the male insured at age 96 eh He wants to see
How much is it possible for him to get
at age
96 so this is what we call living
benefits Of course because he is still alive
he just wants to see How much is
he able to get in
his policy um there are two instances I will
show you here the first one is when
he receives the endowment and
centenarian bonus when he receives it
on schedule meaning 6th year he already received the
cash benefit remember
he is 96 years old So he already received
the age 80 85 90 and 95 centenarian
bonus So the second one
is when he leaves both
his benefits with the company to [ __ ]
late So if we look at the
guaranteed cash value  his is just the
same his accumulated benefits are
just the same the total endowment
benefits are different of course the
total endowment benefits paid that
he received is 3.6 if
he left it with the company It could have earned
more from 3.6 million he could have even
become 16.1 million if he left
his guaranteed cash
benefit with the company So the policy owner has an option
if he wants to take it or if
he wants to leave it the same goes for the
centenarian bonus one has been paid
to him the four instances of the
centenarian bonus at age 80 85 90 and 95
Don't get confused because
you need to remember the ages that ' or the
one instances he left with the
company the 1m that he received if
he left it with the company he could have
earned another 400,000 if
he just left it Okay if
you notice the total benefits that
he received is around 13m if he takes
the endowment benefit and the
centenarian bonus But if
he left it to magac  The payouts that
he can receive at
96 is 26 million. How much is the
total premium he paid? Remember
it's
2668 so multiply it by 10 years. The
total he paid is 2.2 million.
What he will receive either way.
In one instance, he is taking
the benefits. The total he will receive is 13 million.
While in the other,
he left the company with a total of 26 million.
Just take your investment of 2.2
million. How much is your income?
Ask yourself, did you earn money? Did
your policy earn money? In whichever
means you want to enjoy your benefit, they
both earn money. So there is no winner.
The policy owner loses in this plan. Let
's look at the death benefit.
In case he dies at age 96.
We have two instances. The one
he claims to have received is the endowment benefit and
the centenarian bonus or the one
he left with the company to [ __ ] late. Two
instances. But the amount that
can be enjoyed is different. It's almost the same.
terms of the computation, the
guaranteed benefit is 1 million Although
I said earlier that the guaranteed
benefit is 200% of the face amount
in both instances, 100% of the face
amount is already allocated to
our centenarian bonuses,
our centenarian bonuses are just subtracting it
from the guaranteed Deb
benefit, the accumulated dividends are
just the same
7.5 million, the total endowment benefit is
here, the difference comes in when
he takes his benefit, the
total benefit he got is
3.6, if he left the benefit with the
company, he would earn 16 million
since total bonuses of course
he got that, which will be given to him,
if he left it with the company, he
would earn another 400,000 as
mentioned earlier, the total benefit that
the policy owner or the insured will receive
in our first instances is
around 13.2 million, but if the
insured or the policy owner leaves his
payouts, the total he will receive
is 26 million.  including all the
benefits So if you compare 13 million
versus 26 million Of course this is a big
difference but again it
depends on the person It depends on
how you want to enjoy your benefit Do
you want to receive it annually so that it can be
used to supplement your budget or to
pay for your child's enrollment
or if you have nothing else
to spend You can leave it
with the company to [ __ ] late By the way
our dividends interest rate is not
guaranteed because it changes annually It
depends on the dividends that come into the
company This is equally shared among
all the policy owners That's all you
can say How much is the interest rate that will be
divided According to that Are you confused So if
you are confused, don't reach out to
your nearest financial advisor to
explain SAO what is the beauty of the
benefit and you saw it there is
no loss many
will benefit There is a four Generation wealth
plan There is a three Generation wealth plan so it
depends on SAO how you can become a
financial advisor if you don't have a
financial advisor you can comment
here  you can message me on Facebook so
I can answer you and explain
to you what
you are confused about in terms of this. So
thank you for watching. If
you think you know someone who
would benefit from this PL, kindly
share this video with them so
they have an idea of ​​how
good the sunli is. Secure income. Okay, so
I'll wait for that.
[Music]
thank you.